&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：现在我承诺的不仅是更干净的代码风格，而且
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: Now I promised not only a cleaner code style, but
更强大的设计模式。
a more powerful design pattern.
委托是一种设计模式，设计模式应该影响，
Delegation is a design pattern, and design patterns should affect,
他们应该改变你设计代码的方式。
they should change the way that you think about designing a code.
所以，在我们讨论的最后一部分，我想谈谈
And so, in this last part of our discussion, I want to talk about
如何通过授权以不同的方式解决问题，
how delegation should be approached to solve problems differently,
不仅要以不同的方式编写代码，而且要从根本上以不同的方式解决问题。
not just to write code differently, but to solve problems fundamentally differently.
想象一下你有这样一个场景。
Imagine you have a scenario like this.
假设您有一个需要在应用程序中构造的登录页面，并且
Imagine you have a login page that you need to construct in your application and
你将会有两个不同的控制器。
you're going to have two different controllers.
您将有一个代表身份验证部分的AuthController，
You're gonna have an AuthController that represents the authentication part,
例如与服务器通信。
like communicating with the server.
您将有一个LoginFormController，它表示所有
And you're gonna have a LoginFormController, which represents all
UI内容，文本框，按钮，错误消息，以及所有这些，好的。
the UI stuff, the text boxes, and buttons, and error messages, and all of that, okay.
传统的设计方法是，您需要两组行为
The old school way of designing this is that you need both sets of behaviors in
以某种方式，形状或形式，你需要把它们都组合起来，
some way, shape or form, you need them both composed,
或者你需要同时接触他们两个。
or you need access to both of them.
所以老派的方式，
So the old school way,
这就是我们在Java这样的类继承系统中通常会想到的，
which is what we would typically think of in a class inheritance system like Java,
使其中一个成为父类，另一个成为子类。
is you make one of them the parent class, the other one the child class.
然后实例化以获得这个pageInstance。
And then you instantiate to get this pageInstance.
它包含AuthController中的所有方法和AuthController中的所有方法
And it has all the methods from AuthController and all the methods from
此实例中存在的LoginFormController。
the LoginFormController present in this instance.
然后你可以为页面做任何你需要做的事情。
And then you can do whatever you need to do for the page.
这就是解决这个问题的遗传方式
That's sort of how the inheritance way of solving this
问题就会接近它。
problem would have approached it.
这就是我们所谓的通过继承组成。
That's what we called composition thru inheritance.
这是20世纪80年代和90年代关于软件应该如何构建的愿景。
This was the 1980's and 1990's vision for how software should be built.
在90年代中后期的某个地方，你开始听到整个
Somewhere in the mid to late 90s, you started to hear that this whole
15级深层继承链的事情就像一个反模式。
15-level deep inheritance chain thing was like an anti-pattern.
人们开始说，不，我们不想通过
And people started saying, no, no, no, we don't wanna do composition thru
继承，我们想做构图，而不是构图而不是继承。
inheritance, we wanna do composition instead over composition over inheritance.
摆脱所有垂直方向的嵌套链和
Get rid of all those vertically-oriented nested chains and
让我们让这些东西自己组合在一起。
let's just have these things compose themselves together.
所以组成它们的一种方法是使用这两个类，
So one way of composing them is to have these two classes,
实例化其中一个，然后当您实例化另一个时，
to instantiate one of them, and then when you instantiate the other one,
使其成为第一个的属性。
make it a property of the first one.
所以现在我可以访问pageInstance和
So now I have access to all the methods on pageInstance and
offInstance上的所有方法都在一个地方，它们是组合在一起的。
all the methods on offInstance all in one place, they are composed together.
这是做这种作文的一种方法。
That's one way of doing that composition.
然后有人说，好吧，这很难看，因为如果我需要创作更多，我
And then somebody said, well, that's ugly because then if I need to compose more I
得到了所有这些属性，让我们做Mixin。
got all these properties, let's do mixins.
于是我们发明了混音构图的概念，这就是说，
So then we invented the idea of mixin composition, which said,
我将实例化一个ControllerClass和一个AuthControllerClass。
I'm gonna instantiate a ControllerClass and instantiate an AuthControllerClass.
然后我会把所有东西都复制到另一个
And then I'm just gonna copy everything over into the other one.
所以现在所有这些方法都被复制了。
So now all those methods have been copied over.
所有这些都是我们解决问题的不同方式，
All of these are different ways that we've solved the problem,
我想在逻辑上把这两件事分开。
which is I want to logically separate these two things.
但它们需要共存，我才能真正让页面正常工作。
But then they need to coexist for me to actually get the page to work.
所谓共存，我的意思是，它们需要以某种方式组成。
By coexist I mean, they need to be composed in some way.
我们一直在尝试发明不同的方法来组成这些东西。
And we've been trying to invent different ways to compose this things.
那么，代表团对此的回答是什么？
So, what is delegation's answer to this?
委派如何做不同的事情？
How does delegation do things differently?
第一，你所做的关于授权的事情，对不起。
Number one, the thing that you do with delegation, excuse me.
你所做的委派就是你不再考虑父辈和
The thing that you do with delegation is you stop thinking about parent and
孩子，你开始考虑点对点。
child and you start thinking about peer-to-peer.
所以我可以有一个链接到AuthController的LoginFormController。
So I could have a LoginFormController that is linked to an AuthController.
我们必须摆脱这种亲子关系的想法
We have to get rid of this idea of a parent-child and
想想点对点。
think about the peer-to-peer.
我们只是说LoginController链接到AuthController，好吗？
We're gonna just say LoginController is linked to AuthController, all right?
&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：下面是一个用JavaScript编写的代码示例。
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: So here's an example in code of doing that in JavaScript.
我将制作一个AuthController，它上面有一些方法，比如authenticate和
I'm gonna make an AuthController that has methods on it like authenticate and
HandleResponse。
handleResponse.
然后我将创建一个LoginFormController，它在
And then I'm gonna make a LoginFormController, and it has methods on
它类似于表单的onSubmit处理程序和displayError消息。
it like an onSubmit handler for the form and a displayError message.
并且LoginFormController通过原型链接到，
And LoginFormController is linked to, through the prototype chain,
授权控制器。
the AuthController.
但这是两个独立的具体物体。
But these are two separate concrete objects.
他们不像是一个班级
It's not like they're a class for
这些东西，它们实际上是两个独立的物体。
these things, they are actual two separate objects.
如果需要，您可以单独与它们交互。
And you could interact with them separately if you needed to.
但部分时间，他们需要彼此合作。
But part of the time, they need to cooperate with each other.
例如，无论何时我到onSubmit，正如你在这里看到的，
So for example, whenever I got to onSubmit, as you see here,
无论何时转到onSubmit，我都需要在第18行调用this.authenticate。
whenever I go to onSubmit, I need to call this.authenticate on line 18.
但是LoginFormController没有身份验证方法。
But the LoginFormController doesn't have an authenticate method.
因此该方法被委派给AuthControl对象。
And so that method is delegated to the AuthControl object.
所以我们然后运行authenticate方法，但是
So we then run the authenticate method, but
我们要指的这把钥匙是什么？
what is the this key we're gonna point at?
它仍然会指向LoginFormController，对吗？
It's still gonna be pointing at LoginFormController, right?
所以我们实际上所做的是
So what we have actually done is through
原型系统中这个关键字的独角兽魔力，
the unicorn magic of the this key word in the prototype system,
在函数调用期间，我们实际上已经组合了这两个对象。
we have virtually composed these two objects during the function call.
它们现在位于this关键字的共享上下文中，其中
They are now in a shared context over the this keyword where
他们两个都可以互相交谈和分享。
both of them can talk to each other and share with each other.
这里我们调用authenticate方法。
Here we are calling the authenticate method.
但是当authenticate在第4行上显示this.userName时，
But when authenticate says this.userName on line 4,
它实际上引用了LoginFormController上的username属性。
it's actually referring to the username property back on LoginFormController.
因此它能够访问这些属性并在需要时使用它们。
So it's able to access those properties and use them as it needs them.
然后每当handleResponse从服务器返回并且出现错误时，
And then whenever the handleResponse comes back from the server and there's an error,
在第9行，我知道现在有很多箭头，但在第9行，当我们说，
on line 9, I know there is a lot of arrows now, but on line 9 when we say,
this.displayError，我们没有displayError，但谁有呢？
this.displayError, we don't have a displayError, but who does?
LoginFormController。
The LoginFormController.
因此，您可以看到这两个独立的具体对象实际上是如何
So you see how these two separate concrete objects have virtually
在这个共享的背景下彼此组成？
composed each other over the shared this context?
&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：这是一种非常不同的思考方式
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: That's a very different way of thinking about how we
解决软件问题。
solve software.
我们解决软件
We solve software,
我们有两个独立的具体的东西可以做他们自己的工作。
we have two separate concrete things that can do their own work.
但是当他们需要合作的时候，他们合作的方式是没有实例的
But when they need to cooperate, the way they cooperate is not having instance
调用实例a调用instance.b方法。
a call instance a call instance.b method.
他们合作的方式是通过原型链联系起来的，
The way they cooperate is linked through the prototype chain,
它们只是共享一个呼叫上下文。
they just share a call context.
并且它们可以在必要时调用彼此的方法。
And they can call each other's methods as necessary.
&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：该方法的许多好处之一是如果
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: One of the many benefits of that approach is that if
您有单独的对象，这些对象仅通过原型链链接，
you have separate objects that are only linked through a prototype chain,
因为这些对象是分开的，而不是通过
because those objects are separate instead of being wired together through
类层次结构或任何东西，它们变得更易于测试。
class hierarchies or anything, they become much more testable.
可独立测试。
Independently testable.
假设我有这两个对象
So lets say I have these two objects and
我想做的是我想做一个可以测试的模仿。
what I want to do is I want to make a mock that I can test against.
所以让我们模拟一下AuthController。
So let's mock out the AuthController.
我正在通过模拟AuthController来测试LoginFormController。
I'm testing the LoginFormController by mocking the AuthController.
我所要做的就是将LoginFormController原型链接到
All I have to do is have the LoginFormController prototype linked to
我的模拟对象。
my mock object.
我不需要更改代码的任何内容。
I didn't have to change anything about the code.
我只是改变了它的原型连接的地方。
I just change where its prototype linked.
你可以用原型做到，记得吗？
You can do that with a proto, remember?
所以现在我通过模拟AuthController来测试LoginFormController，但是
So now I'm testing the LoginFormController by mocking out the AuthController, but
如果我想测试另一个呢？
what if I wanna test the other one?
如果我想测试AuthController怎么办？
What if I wanna test the AuthController?
我制作了一个MockLoginFormController，它委托给
Well, I make a MockLoginFormController that delegates to
AuthController，现在我正在测试AuthController。
the AuthController, and now I'm testing the AuthController.
我可以完全独立地设置这些测试。
I can set up these tests entirely independent.
我不需要测试依赖注入或任何其他胡说八道。
I don't need test dependency injection or any of that other nonsense.
这些测试完全独立于代码，
These tests are just entirely separate of the code,
它们只是改变原型链发生的位置。
they just change where the prototype chain linkage happens.
我们可以模拟出不同的物体。
And we're able to mock out the different objects.
如果你有三个或四个或者
And that gets even more powerful if you have three or four or
原型链中的五个对象。
five objects that are in the prototype chain.
您可以模拟出不同的部件以进行隔离和测试。
You can mock out different parts to isolate and test.
&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：这就是我的案例
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: So that's my case for
为什么我认为我们上课错过了目标。
why I think we've been missing the mark by doing classes.
我理解为什么有时候甚至没有选择，
I understand why there is sometimes not even an option,
框架为您做出选择。
the framework makes the choice for you.
或者即使你有选择
Or even if you do have an option,
我有时能理解，上课有一种情感依恋。
I understand sometimes that there's an emotional attachment to doing classes.
我得到了所有这些东西。
I get all of that stuff.
但我真的认为如果你认真对待，理解和
But I really think that if you are taking seriously, understanding and
学习JavaScript，努力的一部分是，
learning JavaScript, part of that endeavor is,
如何以最有效的设计方式使用JavaScript？
how do I use JavaScript in its most effectively designed way?
而且我不认为即使有那么多的糖，他们也不会在班级上层层叠起来
And I don't think even with all the sugar they've layered on top of classes
它符合JavaScript的DNA标记。
that it meets the mark of the DNA of JavaScript.
这就是JavaScript固有的功能。
That's what JavaScript does inherently.
JavaScript的作用和
What JavaScript does and
天生就是委派，它做的是原型委派。
does well inherently is delegation, it does prototype delegation.
我想看到的是，我希望看到更多的人接受这一点。
And what I'd like to see is, I'd like to see more people embracing that.
去追求它，而不是试图找到更复杂的东西
And going after that rather than trying to find more complex
在类语法上分层的方法。
ways to layer on class syntax.